Mobile Suit
Rage on! Rage on! Rage on! Gundam!
Moeagare! Moeagare! Moeagare GANDAMU!
You must run forth!
Kimi yo hashire
If you are still burning with furious rage...
Mada ikari ni moeru toshi ga aru nara...
You must fight the towering foe!
Kyodai na teki o
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Uteyo! Uteyo! Uteyo!
Bring to bear the rage of justice, Gundam
Seigi no ikari o butsukero GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Rise once more! Rise once more!
Yomigaeru! Yomigaeru!
Rise once more! Gundam!
Yomigaeru GANDAMU!
You must seize the power!
Kimi yo tsukame
Fly toward the galaxy, Gundam!
Ginga e mukatte tobeyo GANDAMU
Mobile Suit Gundam! Gundam!
Kidou senshi GANDAMU! GANDAMU!
Mr. Ryu, standby okay!
Good!
Amuro, standby for docking.
Ready?
I'm going in, Mr. Ryu!
5... 4... 3...
2... 1...
Laser searcher synchronized.
5... 4...
Gundam B Parts released!
Core Change! Docking, go!
The youthful crew train
as they proceed across Central Asia.
The endless fighting has not let up
since they left Side 7.
Amuro Deserts
You're really focused, aren't you?
So what are you doing?
I'm drawing up combat simulations.
Huh?
We've learned the Zaku's actual performance
from the one we captured.
By entering those parameters
along with Gundam's...
...I'm seeing if I can come up with
more accurate combat patterns.
But... it won't do you any good...
...against the new Gouf mobile suit
that the prisoner talked about.
I've increased the Zaku's performance
by 20% to account for that.
Well. That's our Amuro for you.
Want me to take over?
Thanks. I'm counting on you.
Please do get some sleep, Amuro.
Sure.
How is it going, Bright?
Another young female soldier, huh?
He won't accept the fact that
I'm the commander of this ship.
Ensign Cozun Graham...
...where is Ramba Ral's Gallop,
or whatever it's called?
An officer should know
how to treat another officer.
I've checked the Antarctic Treaty,
Ensign Cozun.
Now, won't you tell us about M'Quve's mines?
I'm afraid I can't talk that easily.
Water...!
Amuro! Come fix it! Fix the plumbing!
The plumbing?
K-Kikka...
...Ms. Mirai's here, right? Ask her.
Mirai! The water!
What's wrong?
K-Kikka...!
I was doing the laundry,
but now the water won't stop!
Amuro, please stay!
Could you check the faucet?!
S-Sure. I'm coming in.
Out of the way, Kikka.
Kikka, what happened to the handle?
It's in the sink.
Huh?
Oh! It's fixed! It's fixed!
You're a lifesaver, Amuro.
Is it completely fixed now?
No...
I think you need to have it fixed properly.
Well, I gotta go.
This Zaku has seen a lot of use.
Will it be all right, Clamp?
Yes, sir.
The overhaul report looks good, sir.
The joints have been replaced
with new ones...
The Fat Uncle may return.
All clear!
What's the Trojan Horse been up to?
Dear?
Why exactly did you accept this mission?
Do you disapprove?
No.
It's just as you think. This is a mission
of personal vengeance for the Zabi family.
However...
...if I destroy the Trojan Horse
and avenge Lord Garma in this battle...
...I'll receive a special two-rank promotion.
My promotion would also
secure the livelihoods of my men.
It's for the men?
And for you.
You'll rub shoulders with the Zabis.
You just wait and see.
I believe in you.
Don't think you'll get out any time soon!
Amateurs.
Didn't even do a proper body search.
You're from Zeon, aren't you?
If you want, you can escape with me.
You seem to misunderstand.
If you're escaping, I'll call for someone.
What?!
Somebody! The prisoner's escaping!
Why, you...!
Somebody! Please come!
The prisoner is escaping! Hurry!
Missiles!
Fire our missiles horizontally!
Tell where they were fired from.
From the ground. 11 o'clock.
So, M'Quve's got a base this far east.
Sorry I'm late!
Scope! Maximum magnification!
Examine the base in front!
Amuro, launch the Gundam!
Roger. Amuro, launching.
I may have to do a mid-air transfer.
Please have the Gunperry ready, Mr. Bright.
Roger.
Mid-air transfer?
Amuro! What do you mean?!
Amuro! Are you sure about this?!
You'll get in trouble with Mr. Bright!
Don't worry. I'm confident
I can explain this to Mr. Bright.
We're going to head out. Ready?
The Guntank has launched.
It's Hayato and Amuro.
What? It's not Ryu? What's going on?
Bright!
Ryu, where are you?
Sayla just told me! The prisoner's escaped!
What?!
I'll get Sayla to search him out!
Meanwhile, I'll take the Guntank...
The Guntank has left.
What?!
It can't be helped...
Hunt down that prisoner.
Shoot him if you have to.
I'm counting on you.
Thank you, Bright. I'll find him somehow.
Thanks.
Operator, check inside the ship!
Quickly!
Knowing that prisoner, I'm sure he's...
...going to try and contact his comrades.
This machine is so hard to tune!
Got it!
Mustang 2, Mustang 2!
This is Cozun!
Transmitting from the Trojan Horse!
Oh, here you are.
We have a message from Cozun, sir.
What?! From Cozun?!
There are three types:
Gundam, Guntank, and Guncannon
Only one of each is on the Trojan Horse.
I don't know if they have fighters...
Is somebody in comm room number 2?
What? There shouldn't be anyone there.
The comm circuit is open.
Let's check the monitor.
The TV circuit has been cut.
Shut off the master comm circuit!
Yes, sir!
Piece of junk!
Bright. How much information
do you think was leaked?
Don't know.
There's the enemy in front of us...
And it looks like he's called in
Ramba Ral's Gouf team, too.
They're coming in on your right, Hayato!
I see 'em!
Right on, Hayato.
For a ground base like this...
...the firepower and mobility
of the Guntank is just fine.
Mr. Bright doesn't really
understand tactics yet.
Fighting everything with the Gundam
isn't always the best solution.
Anything from Captain M'Quve?!
Yes. He's sent out Dopps to support us.
I've been unable to make contact since then.
Just what are they thinking?!
Why would they hit a mine like this,
with no strategic value at all?
Ensign.
What is it?
Ramba Ral's Gallop is on its way
to give us support.
Ramba Ral?
Oh, Garma's revenge team.
Does that mean... the infamous
Trojan Horse is attacking our base?
All right! Good, Hayato!
It's only a question of time
before we take down that base.
Cozun. You just get out of there safely.
Mobile Suit
Gundam
He's coming! He's coming!
Defense attack! Go, Haro!
The prisoner's headed for Hatch 18!
Is anybody there?!
Dopps! And there's something
approaching on the ground!
What?!
Must be the Gallop the prisoner mentioned.
Sayla can deal with the prisoner somehow.
We need Ryu and Kai!
And Amuro must transfer to the Gundam!
Ryu! Kai! Can you hear me?
Enemy reinforcements have appeared!
All right! I'm launching!
Kai, in the Guncannon! Now launching!
Right! Balance is good!
I'm landing!
I can see it now. Damn Trojan Horse.
There's a Dopp formation,
here to support us!
I'm off. I don't like to say things like
"this time for sure", but...
The Trojan Horse has three mobile suits
in action. Please be careful.
It makes me wish we had three Goufs.
If Cozun escapes, make sure he's rescued.
Of course, my dear.
Ghien! Stetch! Keep up with me!
We're launching!
Amuro! Dopps! Turn to left!
Just five or six Dopps...!
Amuro! Do you read?!
What is it, Mr. Bright?
Retreat, while the Guncannon
and the Core Fighter cover you!
Transfer to the Gundam!
But...!
Aim properly, Hayato! These Dopps
shouldn't be a problem for the Guntank!
I-I'm doing the best I can, but...!
Are you all right, Hayato!
I'm fine!
To your left! Zakus!
Zakus?! And the new mobile suit!
The prisoner called it a Gouf!
- Hayato! Fire!
- Roger!
That Zaku's moving faster than I calculated!
Amuro! Return!
We're heading back, Hayato!
The Guntank's useless against moving foes!
Kai! Do you read?! Cover us!
What?! You gotta be kidding?
Move the White Base forward!
It's too much for just the Guncannon!
All right!
Mirai, we'll charge with the White Base!
Yes, sir!
Port-side! Keep that Gallop away!
Amuro, do you read?!
We're opening the hatch! Get back!
Roger!
As long as I have this...
Ms. Sayla! Where's the prisoner?!
He's in the airlock!
He's going to escape!
You can't open it with a sidearm.
It's not that cheap.
Ms. Sayla, step back!
Good...
M-Ms. Sayla...!
Don't feel guilty.
It could be us next time.
R-Right...
Control system is transferred!
Ready for launch!
Amuro! Is the transfer complete?
Ms. Sayla? Are you allowed there?
I'm sorry, but I have to be here for now.
Sayla. Where's Cozun, the prisoner?
I'm sorry. He's... dead.
I see.
At least we've stopped
any further information leaks.
Amuro! Provide support for Kai! Hurry!
Cover for White Base is...
Hey!
The enemy's clever!
They're spreading out in four directions!
Which is the strongest?!
The new mobile suit in the center, the Gouf!
Gouf... The Gouf, huh?
This is the end for you,
Federation mobile suit!
It's going to explode!
Amuro, launch now.
Please take care of the Guncannon in front.
Here I go!
Kai!
It's not working!
The computer's patterns can't keep up!
Was the data inaccurate?
We have to cover the Gundam!
Concentrate fire only on the Gouf in front!
Damn! The shock wave from the blast
screwed up the joints.
Must I fall back without a fight?!
If only the ground forces had held up better,
we could have managed...
Ghien! Stetch! We're retreating!
Return to the Gallop at Point R!
I told you to launch in the Gundam.
The enemy was weak, so we survived. But...
It's a fact that the Guntank was
the best choice for attacking a fortress...
But the Gallop joined in!
Yes.
A soldier can't predict everything
about an operation!
Never disobey orders!
That's a violation of military regulations.
Regulations?!
Yes.
It's a necessity during combat.
I understand...
...but are we regular soldiers now?
Be careful.
Yes, sir.
Amuro's thinking hard and
doing the best he can, Bright.
If I just accepted that, we'd all end up dead.
Right, Ryu?
I suppose that's logical...
That was a complete disaster.
The Gouf's and Zaku's movements
are completely different...
...depending on environment and pilot.
I guess I'll have to start over
from the beginning.
I can't really agree with you.
Job can do it.
Even Omur has done simulations.
But...
No repairs on the Cannon?
The spare arm is being repaired
in the workshop.
Ah. So, what do you think, Mirai?
He may be too young,
but that doesn't make him unsuitable.
I think it would be better if we
entrusted Ryu with the Gundam.
You've already decided, haven't you, Bright?
To take Amuro off of the Gundam?
Yeah.
We don't have enough time
to wait for one boy to grow up.
I know this is no training ground, but...
...maybe we can give Amuro a bit of a rest.
But...
Amuro's a special boy.
I have a strong feeling about this.
Mirai, I want you to agree with me.
Amuro!
So, you heard us.
Don't.
It's spared us the trouble
of explaining it all to him.
You think so?
Amuro?!
Where are you going?
I'm leaving the White Base.
Take care.
Huh?
What?!
I'm getting off the ship.
What's wrong?!
Mr. Bright and Ms. Mirai say
I'm no longer necessary.
And so I'm leaving the ship.
W-Wait!
Don't stop me!
Amuro!
Mr. Bright! The Gundam is launching!
Come in, Gundam!
Who's on board?! Gundam!
Come in!
Marker! Can you close the hatch?!
Impossible! Catapult is launching!
It's Amuro! Amuro's...
Amuro!
That Amuro...!
Alone with the Gundam...
...Amuro attacks M'Quve's mining facility.
That is where he sees...
...Kycilia, a leader of the Zabi family.
Will M'Quve's base be destroyed?
Or will the Adzam melt down the Gundam?
Mobile Suit Gundam. Next episode...
Zeon's Secret Mine.
Next Time
Zeon's Secret Mine
Will you be able to survive?
Amuro, do not look back
The star shining far off in space...
Amuro, it's your homeland where you were born
Do you remember the days of your childhood?
The morning when you woke up in warmth?
Amuro, do not look back, Amuro...
A man must hide his tears, hide his tears
Only look to tomorrow, to tomorrow forever...